

Prabin Bhatta

Date of Birth: 16/06/1992 | **Nationality:** Nepalese | **Gender:** Male **Phone Number:** (+44) 7459286205 | **Email:** prabin20101@gmail.com

Website: https://www.bhattaprabin.com.np/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/prabinbhatta/

Github: https://github.com/bhattaprabin

Address: 3 RedMarle Road, LE3 1PH, Leicester, United Kingdom

Professional Summary

Objective dedicated, passionate .NET developer with 3.5 years of experience in software analysis, design, development, enhancement, and testing, looking for software developer roles. Returning to the workforce after taking some time off to pursue higher education while staying engaged with the programming through final year project in .NET.

WORK EXPERIENCE

4Pix Solutions Pvt. Ltd | *Full Stack .NET Developer* | Kathmandu, Nepal

Sept 2018 - Feb 2021

EHRP-MIS | Earthquake Housing Reconstruction Programme

- ❖ Built the backend, database, and implemented code to production server as per requirements from government authority named National Reconstruction Authority (NRA). Additionally, reviewed, analyzed, and tested code from assistant developers to assure quality of project – Web API, MVC, C#, Oracle, Stored Procedures, Views, JavaScript, JSON, jQuery, DataTable, Version controlling with SVN and GIT, Entity Framework, CSS, XML, HTML, Microsoft Azure.
- teratively developed and configured the system, demonstrated it to clients for approval and feedback, and prepared user guides and technical documentation.
- Got opportunity to lead project within 1.5 years with responsibility to manage team of four developers.
- Regular meetings and stand ups to assure that stakeholders requirements are met.

Percoid IT Solutions | .NET MVC Developer | Lalitpur, Nepal

Jan 2017 – Feb 2018

- ❖ Worked on different projects such as advertisement management system, Content Resource Management (CRM) System Web API, MSSQL, Knockouts.js, Angular.js, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Razor, Dapper, Entity Framework, .NET Core, ASP.NET Web Forms, Classic ASP.Net, LINQ, stored Procedures.
- Developed skills to work under pressure to meet deadlines with proper technical documentations and timely report to project manager.

Leicester Phone Repair | Mobile Technician (Part-Time) | Leicester United Kingdom

Nov 2021 – Present

- Repairing and replacing different types of IPhone's and Samsung's LCDs and batteries.
- ❖ Installation of Windows Operating System and Microsoft office Package on Customer's Laptops.
- Selling of mobile phone accessories delivering better customer service.

EDUCATION

De Montfort University | *MSC in Information System Management* | Leicester, United Kingdom Oct 2021 – Sept 2022

- Cumulative Percentage: 69% (Merit)
- Core Modules: OOP (Java), Database System and Design, Computer System and Network, E-Commerce S/M.

Janakpur Engineering College | Bachelor's in Computer Engineering | Kathmandu, Nepal

2011 - 2015

- Cumulative Percentage: 64%
- Core Modules: C/C++, DBMS (MSSQL), Data Structure and Algorithms, Agile Development.

Tilottama Higher Secondary School | +2 HSEB | Tilottama, Nepal

2009 - 2011

Cumulative Percentage: 64.62%

ACADEMIC PROJECTS

PEMS | Post-Earthquake Management System

Final Year Project (De Montfort University)

A web-based .NET application system that can manage the reconstruction process of disaster-damaged houses that can process survey data from damage scenarios in the affected areas after an earthquake occurs and can be useful for the decision-making teams in organizing and formulating the strategic post-disaster response.

- ❖ N-tier Architecture pattern, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ADO.Net Entity Data Model, Entity Framework, MSSQL, Chart.js, jQuery DataTable.
- ❖ Features like Survey Module, Inspection Module, Payment module and Report module to represent the reconstruction process.
- GitHub Reference: https://github.com/bhattaprabin/PEMS_DeMontfort_Project

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother Tongue(s): Nepali

Other Language(s):

	Listening/ Reading	Speaking	Writing
English	B2	B2	B2

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

ORGANISATIONAL SKILLS

Being a developer at 4Pix Solutions, I acquired the skills to.

- ❖ Manage the product, upload the code to production server and update stored procedures to database server.
- Communicate with clients to gather requirements and present product features through training and Microsoft Teams.
- Develop problem-solving, communicative and leadership skills with ability to achieve deadlines.

Being a Mobile Repair Technician at Leicester Phone Repair, I managed to.

- ❖ Develop interpersonal skills along with confidence that I am quick learner.
- ❖ Adapt promptly to change and possess excellent customer service experience.
- Develop a positive attitude.

TEACHING EXPERIENCE

Durga Shaikshik Griha | *Secondary School Teacher*, | Rupandehi, Nepal

Aug 2015 – Dec 2016

- ❖ Taught compulsory mathematics to students in grades 8, 9, and 10.
- Served as a hostel warden for 10th-grade students.
- Regularly monitored, counselled, and mentored Student through academic prizes and extracurricular activities.

Department for Education (HyperionDev skills Bootcamps)

Feb 2023 – Present

As, I am passionate about software development I am now shaping my skills in python through the skills bootcamp funded by Department for Education (Gov.UK) for the duration of 3 months.

- Python web development
- SQI and Django framework for Python in the backend.

^{***}Ready to relocate ***